Mary Cris G. Alegria

825-288-2890

cris.alegria28@hotmail.com 148 Corner Meadows Way, Northeast Calgary Alberta, T3N 1Y4

PERSONAL PROFILE

An international student and a newcomer in Canada with over 10 years of experience in IT, Administration, Education, Retail Industry. My working experiences helped me a lot to be highly motivated and able to handle a broad range of tasks, have good problemsolving abilities, technical skills, have a good working etiquette and good communication skills.

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

University of St. La Salle • Bacolod, Philippines

Diploma in Software Development

Bow Valley College • Calgary, Canada January 2023 - present

SKILLS

- Advanced Microsoft Office / 365
- Basic Knowledge in SAP
- Support Staff Training and Development
- Advanced Knowledge in company's school and financial system
- Editing/Designing (using Adobe Photoshop)
- · Making Presentation Report using Prezi
- JavaScript, C++, PHP

REFERENCES

Ernesto J. Ybañez Jr. MIT Coordinator, Computer Center University of St. La Salle – Bacolod City, Philippines Tel # (63)(34)4321187 loc 161 / 09228755488

Mahmoud Sayed Korany Operations Manager Orbits' Pioneers Education Co. , Khobar Saudi Arabia Tel # (+966)54 551 4211 / mahmod19733@hotmail.com

Ria T. Ablong Store Manager Supervalue Inc. (SM Supermarket-Bacolod), Philippines Tel # 09297111745 ria.tacoloy@gmail.com

WORK HISTORY

IT Coordinator and School Secretary (FULL TIME)

Orbits' Pioneers Education Co. • Al Khobar, Saudi Arabia September 2016 – October 2022

- School Website Administrator/ Updating School Events on school website and other social media accounts like Facebook and Instagram.
- Making Monthly Attendance and Salary Report for all employees
- Preparing and Checking all needed facilities for the Monthly Meetings / Trainings
- Designing School Tarpaulin, Banner, Flyers
- Set up equipment for employee and student use, performing and ensuring proper installation of cables, operating systems, or appropriate software.
- Making Timetables and Substitution Schedule
- Making Report Cards based on Ministry of Education Format and Printing Report Cards for Students
- Notifying the parents thru Pioneers SMS System if the child is absent
- Checking and Making Employees' Monthly Attendance Report
- Encoding Data / Creating User Profile for Teachers and Students in the School System
- Preparing and Processing Manpower Request to Philippine Labor Office in Saudi Arabia

IT Staff (FULL TIME)

Edulynx Co. • Bacolod, Philippines June 2014 – May 2016

- Installing and configuring computer hardware, software, systems, networks, printers and scanners
- Talking to students/teachers/computer users to determine the nature of problems.
- Introducing the use/ purpose of the company software in front of the class.
- Investigating, diagnosing and solving computer software and hardware faults
- · Checking electrical equipment for electrical safety
- Managing consumables and other supplies

Administrative Assistant (FULL TIME)

Supervalue Inc. • Bacolod, Philippines July 2012 – March 2014

- Preparing Monthly Report for Operation (using SAP)
- · Processing of Business Permits
- Retrieving documents and maintaining data entry applications
- Managing the Cleaning Staff, Tenants/Concessionaire and Security personnel
- · Checking Tenant's Area and Updating their Lease of Contract
- Weekly Guard mounting and Daily meeting with Cleaning Staff to discuss some issues in the store.
- Processing Case Filing Settlement
- Writing meeting notes
- Maintaining filing systems.
- Answering phone calls and responding to faxes
- Scheduling appointments and travel arrangements

Student Assistant (PART TIME)

University of St. La Salle, Computer Center • Bacolod, Philippines November 2009 – May 2012

- Serves as helpdesk/technical support for students, teachers and faculties
- Installing and configuring computer hardware, software, systems, networks, printers and scanners
- Preparing the enrollment facilities, and computer laboratory for course reservation
- · Cleaning the computer equipment and computer laboratory